tomsplanner.com 2019-04-06

# Privacy Statement | TomsPlanner

At tomsplanner.com, your privacy is our priority. We are committed to protecting your privacy at all times, in all situations. The information we collect about you if you become a member is used to process your orders and to provide a more personalized experience on our site.

 **How Do We Use the Information We Collect?**

If you become a tomsplanner.com user, we ask you to fill out a form that requests your name and e-mail address.

Your personal information is collected, used and disclosed for purposes including creating an account, carrying out or responding to your requests, verifying your identity, improving our services, communicating with you, purposes relating to any third party acquisition or potential acquisition of an interest in Tom’s Lab BV or its assets (like Tom’s Planner NV), or any other purposes outlined at the time you provide the information. We may not be able to do these things without your personal information.

We may provide personal information about you to service providers who assist us in providing our products and services. These may include organizations that assist us with archival, research, mail and delivery, auditing, professional consulting, financial and legal advisory, security or technology services.

 **Our Use of Log Files**

When you visit our site we automatically log your computer’s IP address, browser type and access times. We utilize this information to conduct site performance evaluations, to see where visitors are coming from and to keep track of click stream data (that is, information about which screens our users visit on our site). This data helps us to determine what content our members find most appealing so that we can maximize your enjoyment of the site. Users who do not register or log in as members may browse the site without providing any personal information.

 **Gantt charts Data**

We store your Gannt chart data securely and only provide access by your security credentials or the security credentials of other Tom’s Planner users you chose to collaborate with. As an application, Tom’s Planner stores information on charts saved, descriptions, meta-data and any other associated information required to provide a useful charting application. We record and track clickstream data in aggregate to help us better understand user behaviour within Tom’s Planner and provide you with tailored information (based on your behaviour) on how to use Tom’s Planner best.

 **Site Security**

All tomsplanner.com employees are required to take your personal information very seriously. The information is ID and password protected and our Web security is reviewed regularly.

 **Communication**

From time to time we may send out email messages alerting you that products are available, to remind you about providing feedback, explaining you how to use Tom’s Planner or one of it’s new features best or for promotional offers. In addition, you will receive communication from us 1) if you contact us for a particular reason, 2) to receive your account details, or 3) we need to contact you for administrative purposes such. Administrative e-mails will not contain promotional materials.

 **Legal Disclaimer**

Though we make every effort to preserve user privacy, we may need to disclose personal information when required by law wherein we have a good-faith belief that such action is necessary to comply with a current judicial proceeding, a court order or legal process served on our Web site.

 **Our Use of Cookies**

Cookies are pieces of information that your browser stores on your computer’s hard drive which identify your computer. We may use session cookies to provide a seamless experience on the site and to combine with our log files so that we can understand our site traffic and analyze our demographic information in aggregate form. Any such information will be aggregated and not linked to particular individuals unless required by law. The default settings of browsers like Internet Explorer always allow cookies, but users can easily erase cookies from their hard-drive, block all cookies, or receive a warning before a cookie is stored. Please note that some parts of the Website may not function fully for users that disallow cookies.

 **Europe and the GDPR**

Tom’s Planner itself is compliant with the EU General Data Protection Regulation EU 2016/679 (GDPR). Some of our service providers are not GDPR compliant yet but have indicated they will be on or before May 25, 2018. The service providers that Tom’s Planner uses and are of any interest in relation to the GDPR are: Google, AWS, Freshdesk, Mailchimp, FastSpring, Avangate and Postmark.

Your Feedback is Always Welcome

We welcome your comments and questions about our privacy policy – or anything else you might want to talk about. Contact us.

Last updated: Feb 21st 2018
